Phonetics is the study of sound in human speech.
语音学是研究人类语音的学科
Linguistic analysis of language around the world is used to
语言分析
break down human words into their smallest sound segments.
会将人类语言切分成最小的音段
In any given language,
对于任一种语言
some number of phonemes define the distinct sounds in that language.
我们可以用若干音位来定义不同的发音
In US English, there are generally 39 to 44 phonemes to find.
在美国英语中 大概有 39 到 44 个音位
A Grapheme, in contrast,
相反 一个字母
is the smallest distinct unit that can be written in a language.
则是书面语的最小独立单元
In US English the smallest grapheme set we can
美国英语能定义的最小字素集
define is a set of the 26 letters in the alphabet plus a space.
是字母表的 26 个字母加上一个空格
Unfortunately, we can't simply map
很遗憾 我们没有办法将
phonemes to grapheme or individual letters because some
音位与字素或与单个字母对应起来
letters map to multiple phonemes sounds and
因为有些字母对应多个音位
some phonemes map to more than one letter combination.
有些音位则不仅对应一种字母组合
For example, in English the C letter sounds different in cat, chat, and circle.
比如 英语里的字母 C 在 cat、chat 和 circle 里的发音都不一样
Meanwhile, the phoneme E sound we hear in receive,
而我们在 receive、beet 和 beat 里听到的音位 E
beat, and beat, is represented by different letter combinations.
又是以不同的字母组合表示的
Here's a sample of a US English phoneme set called Arpabet.
这是美国英语音位集的一个样本 叫做 Arpabet
Arpabet was developed in 1971 for speech recognition research,
Arpabet 于 1971 年开发而出 旨在研究语音识别
and contains thirty nine phonemes,
其中包括 39 个音位
15 vowel sounds and 24 consonants,
15 个元音和 24 个辅音
each represented as a one or two letter symbol.
每个元音或辅音都由一个或两个字母符号表示
Check the reference section for links to the full set.
要查看整个集合 请查阅参考部分
Phonemes are often a useful intermediary between speech and text.
音位往往是语音和文本间的实用媒介
If we can successfully produce an acoustic model that decodes a sound signal into
如果我们能建立一种声学模型 将声音信号解码成音位
phonemes the remaining task would be to map those phonemes to their matching words.
那剩下的工作就只是将音位与相应的单词匹配起来了
This step is called Lexical Decoding,
这个过程叫词汇解码
and is based on a lexicon or dictionary of the data set.
需要依赖数据集的词典或字典来进行
Why not just use our acoustic model to translate directly into words?
为什么不将声学模型直接翻译成文字呢？
Why take the intermediary step?
为什么要有中间这一步？
That's a good question and there are systems
这是个很好的问题
that do translate features directly to words.
还真有些系统能把特征直接翻译成文字
This is a design choice and depends on the dimensionality of the problem.
这取决于设计目的和问题的维数
If we want to train a limited vocabulary of words we might just skip the phonemes,
如果我们想训练的词汇数量有限 那我们可以跳掉音位这一步
but if we have a large vocabulary converting to smaller units first,
但如果词汇量很大 那就要先转换成较小的单元
reduces the number of comparisons that need to be made in the system overall.
以便减少整个系统需要进行的对比数